Newspaper Accounts of the General Strike of 1926 and Related Matters in Great Britain on Microfilm 5565 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Newspaper Accounts of the General Strike of 1926 and Related Matters in Great Britain on Microfilm
1922-1934
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
British Gazette
5565 mf
0.22 cubic feet
2 microfilm reels
Clippings (information artifacts), microfilm.
Microfilmed articles from British newspapers concerning the General Strike of 1926.
5664264
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, September 26, 2012
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 18, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The 1926 general strike in the United Kingdom lasted 10 days, from May 3, 1926 to May 13, 1926. It was called by the general council of the Trades Union Congress (TUC) in an unsuccessful attempt to force the British government to act to prevent wage reduction and worsening conditions for 800,000 locked-out coal miners. Some 1.7 million workers went out, especially in transport and heavy industry. The government was ready and enlisted middle class volunteers to maintain cover for the strikers. There was little violence and the TUC gave up in defeat. In the long run, there was little impact on trade-union activity or industrial relations.
Scope and Contents
Microfilmed articles from British newspapers concerning the General Strike of 1926.
A negative copy is available upon request.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
General Strike, Great Britain, 1926; Great Britain; British Gazette
5664264
- American publications, 1922-1934. (Reel 2)
  - Sunday Express, 1926; 1 (Reel 1)
    Scope and Contents
    May 2, 1926.
  - Sunday Worker, 1926; 2 (Reel 1)
  - Daily Herald, 1926; 3 (Reel 1)
  - Daily Telegraph, 1926; 4 (Reel 1)
    May 3, 1926.
  - Evening Standard, 1926; 5 (Reel 1)
  - Daily Chronicle, 1926; 6 (Reel 1)
    May 4, 1926.
  - Daily Express, 1926; 7 (Reel 1)
  - Daily Telegraph, 1926; 8 (Reel 1)
  - British Worker Official Strike News Bulletin, 1926; 9 (Reel 1)
    May 5-19, 1926
  - Daily Mail, 1926; 10 (Reel 1)
    May 7, 1926.
  - British Gazette, 1926; 11 (Reel 1)
    May 8, 1926.
  - Daily Express, 1926; 12 (Reel 1)
  - Daily Mail, 1926; 13 (Reel 1)
  - Daily Telegraph, 1926; 14 (Reel 1)
  - Daily Mail, 1926; 15 (Reel 1)
    May 9, 1926.
  - British Gazette, 1926; 16 (Reel 1)
    May 10, 1926.
  - British Gazette, 1926; 17 (Reel 1)
    May 11, 1926.
  - Daily Mail, 1926; 18 (Reel 1)
  - Daily Telegraph, 1926; 19 (Reel 1)
  - British Gazette, 1926; 20 (Reel 1)
    May 12, 1926.
  - Daily News, 1926; 21 (Reel 1)
  - British Gazette, 1926; 22 (Reel 1)
    May 13, 1926.
  - The Times, 1926; 23 (Reel 1)
  - Daily News, 1926; 24 (Reel 1)
    May 14, 1926.
  - Daily Express, 1926; 25 (Reel 1)
    May 15, 1926.
  - Daily Mail, 1926; 26 (Reel 1)